<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Haris Muhammad</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Haris Muhammad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>H. M.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 19:53:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 11:36:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Summary I am an accomplished Software Engineer specializing in Full Stack JavaScript with over three years of experience, most of which was spent in high-level, leadership roles. I served as the technical advisor for two startups and led the development of a successful MVP. CUrrently, I serve as the Client Development Lead at FLIP.
Technical Skills   Experienced:
 Full Stack Development, Web and Mobile Applications, Servers and Networking, Database Scheming, API Designing, Static Analysis, Unit Testing, Version Control, Git Flow, Agile/Scrum    Languages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Teaching Others Helps You Learn</title>
      <link>/essays/why-teaching-others-helps-you-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 19:53:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/essays/why-teaching-others-helps-you-learn/</guid>
      <description>I know programming, but none of my family or friends understand it. Yet, I still make a sincere effort to explain my work. Some common questions I get from them are:
 What does all this text do? What&amp;rsquo;s with all the colors? Is this hacking/cracking? What exactly are cookies?  None of these are informed questions but I enjoy answering them nonetheless. They may seem like a waste of time for someone with expertise, but you can still learn a lot from these basic questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 19:36:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello My name is Haris, and I&amp;rsquo;m the owner of this website.
Here, I explain my programming in-depth and share essays on my various interests, particularly books, music, and education. I don&amp;rsquo;t post often and instead focus on depth of content. The best way to stay up-to-date is through the site&amp;rsquo;s RSS.
To reach me:
 email at hmuhammad+blog {at} outlook {dot} com see my resume here browse my coding projects at github visit my profile at linkedin  Although it may not be much, thank you for taking the time to read and visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 18:22:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>These are some projects I worked on that are either open-source or non-private. Licensing varies for each, so please read the README or LICENSE for each repo.
To find out more about myself, please check out the about page or my resume.
Narnia: Social Media for Fashion (iOS/Android) Narnia: Login, Feed, and Search Screens  Repo link: →
Technical stack:
 React React Native NodeJS Express MySQL Xcode (for builds)  Narnia is a project aimed at creating a rich social media platform designed for fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning How to Program (and Plenty of Other Skills)</title>
      <link>/essays/learning-how-to-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 22:50:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/essays/learning-how-to-program/</guid>
      <description>Almost everyone claims to have the course or curriculum for learning code, be it giant colleges or small startups. However, I believe programming is one those skills that cannot be truly learned from lecturing or reading. It is a practical skill, much like playing an instrument or delivering a speech, that needs practical action. It is easy to teach the theory (and with programming, that is still a must), but making the transition from idealized textbooks to real-world problems demands real exposure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World</title>
      <link>/essays/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 17:45:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/essays/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Welcome. This is my personal website and its initial setup right now. GitHub is serving as host, Hugo is the blogging engine, and the theme is this one heavily modified. Although there&amp;rsquo;s plenty to fix and finish, a start&amp;rsquo;s a start.
Hugo definitely presents a far steeper learning curve than Jekyll, and its benefits are not apparent yet. But, giving any tech a proper run-through is important, and I consider a proper run-through as getting to a production MVP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>